Ahmed Ali Sayed

Full Stack Developer 0111 291 22 33

AhmedAliSayed13@gmail.com

📍 17 Mohamed Mostafa Street, Imbaba, Giza

Personal Information

Birth date: 21th February 1995

Military Status: ExemptedMarital Status: Engaged

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmed-ali-a267b2172/

Github: https://github.com/AhmedAliSayed13

Objective

An ambitious and self-motivated web developer with a considerable technical skill who possesses self- discipline and ability to work with minimum of supervision. Able to play a key role in website development to ensure maximum accessibility, user experience and usability. A quick learner who can absorb new ideas and can communicate clearly and effectively.

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, Assuit University
Class of 2014 - 2018
Department Information System (IS)
General Grade Good

Experience

Senior Full Stack Developer at PK Saudi Company (Software House) (Full Time)

(August 2019 — Present), (6 October- Egypt)

Responsibilities:

- Writing clean code for the front and back end of the software
- Creating servers and databases for the back end of the software
- Helping with the design and development of software
- Testing and debugging software to keep it optimized
- Ensuring cross-platform compatibility and optimization
- Testing and maintaining the responsive design of applications
- Developing APIs and RESTful services

- Keeping up with technological advances to optimize their software
- Considering security, maintenance, scalability, and more when developing

Full Stack Developer at Kabtech Corp Company (Digital Transformation) (Part Time)

(January 2019 — February 2020), (Remotely)

Responsibilities:

- Writing clean code for the front and back end of the software
- Creating servers and databases for the back end of the software
- Ensuring cross-platform compatibility and optimization
- Developing APIs and RESTful services
- · Keeping up with technological advances to optimize their software
- Considering security, maintenance, scalability, and more when developing

Back End Developer at Rekaz Company (Petrol Station System) (Full Time)

(June 2018 — July 2019), (Remotely)

Responsibilities:

- Integration of user-facing elements developed by a front-end developers with server side logic
- Creating servers and databases for the back end of the software
- Ensuring cross-platform compatibility and optimization
- Developing APIs and RESTful services
- Keeping up with technological advances to optimize their software
- Considering security, maintenance, scalability, and more when developing

Technical Skills

- Laravel Framework
- **❖** Codeigniter Framework
- Wordpress Management System
- ❖ Fat Free Framework
- PHP
- Vue is
- Lumen Micro Framework
- Restful API
- Wordpress API
- ❖ Laravel API
- Git/Github
- Html / Html5
- Boostrap
- CSS / CSS3
- Jquery
- **❖** Javascript
- SASS
- Create Custom Plugin(Wordpress)

- Create Child theme (Wordpress)
- ❖ Database(Mysql / SQL)
- Json (JavaScript Object Notation)
- ❖ Ajax (Asynchronous JavaScript And XML)
- Firebase
- Click Up
- Trello
- PhotoShop CS6 (BASIC)

Integrations, APIs, and third party

- ❖ Facebook Integration(After Login Get Account information as number of followers and account URL and another data)
- ❖ Twitter Platform(login with twitter account and get time line of posts and account Information)
- ❖ Instagram Platform(login with instagram account and get account Information)
- ❖ Snapchat Platform(login with Snapchat account and get account Information)
- ❖ Youtube Platform (get channel information)
- ❖ Authentication with Google Account
- ❖ Google map Integration (get nearby location, current location)
- ❖ Google drive Integration (upload files to special account)
- PayPal / Stripe Payment Method Integration
- ❖ Aliphia Payment Method Integration
- ❖ FawryPay Payment Method Integration
- **❖** Ldap Integration
- whatsapp instance provider Integration(login, send message, create groups, get conversations, Any Features in whatsapp)(provider is chat api)
- **❖** Zoom Integration
- ❖ dafater Integration (financial and management systems)
- ❖ PTS Integration with automation device

Projects

★ Website For ministry of Education in Saudi Arabia (MOE)

- This is portal to show (news and visions and message and projects) about ministry of education in Saudi Arabia
- Technology: Wordpress and jquery and css and html and child theme and Custom Plugin and Mysql and integrate with twitter platform

* Website For PCD Company in Saudi Arabia (PCD)

- This is ecommerce website to sale Gaming PC and its hardware
- Technology: Wordpress and jquery and css and html and child theme and Custom Plugin and Mysql

* Website for PK Saudi Company (PK)

- This is website for PK Saudi Company to display more information about comapny
- Technology: Wordpress and jquery and css and html and child theme and Custom Plugin and Mysql and sass

* Travel2drive Website (T2D)

- This is website to Get a driver's license online in USA
- Technology: Wordpress and jquery and css and html and child theme and Custom Plugin and Mysql and integrate with Paypal

* College Housing Website (CH)

- This is real state website to rent house or room for students in USA
- Technology: Wordpress and jquery and css and html and child theme and Custom Plugin and Mysql

★ Website For Ozone Company for Social Media in Saudi Arabia (OZO)

- This is platform to collect infulencers of social medias and benefauries to make order of service from infulencers
- Technology: FatFree Framwork and jquery and css and html and Mysql and Boostrap and Github

* Website For Agency Building of Ministry of Education in Saudi Arabia

- This is system to management all projects and contractors in every City in Saudi Arabia
- Technology: Laravel Framwork and jquery and css and html and Mysql and Boostrap and Github

* Website for Jumeirah Company (Jumeirah)

- This is real state website to sale house in Egypt
- Technology: Wordpress and jquery and css and html and child theme and Custom Plugin and Mysql

* Website for Almaali Medical Clinic in Saudi Arabia (Almaali)

- This is website to booking any doctor appointments online in Almaali Medical Clinic
- Technology: Laravel Framwork and Vue js and jquery and css and html and Mysql and Boostrap and Github and API

* Website for Ministry of Education in Saudi Arabia to show Statistic

- This is Portal To Show Some Statistic To make the task of decision makers what is the right decision
- Technology: Laravel Framwork and jquery and css and html and Mysql and Boostrap and Github and Chart js

★ Website for Ministry of Education in Saudi Arabia to show key performance indicator (kpi)

- This is System Show Some Statistic To display any contractor success in special city and another not and what is the reason of this
- Technology: Laravel Framwork and jquery and css and html and Mysql and Boostrap and Github and Chart is

* Website for Akeed company

- This is website for providing online courses
- Technology: Codeignitor Framwork and jquery and css and html and Mysql and Boostrap and Github

* School Management System

- This is system management every part in school as Absence of students, academic schedule, online lectures, exams, staff management ...
- Technology: Codeignitor Framwork and jquery and css and html and Mysql and Boostrap and Github and integration with zoom

★ Website for 4A Tech Company

- This is website for 4A Tech Company to display more information about comapny
- Technology: Laravel and jquery and Boostrap and css and html and Mysql and sass

* System for Rekaz Company

- This is system for managing a group of petrol stations inside Saudi Arabia
- Technology: Laravel and jquery and Boostrap and css and html and Mysql and sass

* For More Projects Visit My Portfolio.

http://ahmed-ali-portfolios.herokuapp.com/portfolio

Additional Skills

- * Wrote Clean Code
- ★ Responsive Web Design
- ★ Design Patterns (MVC)
- ★ Familiarity with code versioning tools
- * Know how to deal with different screen sizes to provide responsive Website
- **★** Good in organizing tasks
- ★ Quick learner and ability to learn new concepts
- ★ Problem solving skills and code practices
- * Ability to understand business requirements and translate them into technical requirements
- * Familiar with web development and content management system
- ★ Customize Open Source Project

Learning Books

- ❖ A Handbook of Agile software Craftsmanship
- ❖ Laravel Up & Running A Framework for Building Modern PHP Apps
- ❖ Vue.js Up & Running BUILDING ACCESSIBLE AND PERFORMANT WEB APPS
- ❖ Wordpress for Beginners Free eBook Wp35
- ❖ Learning PHP, MySQL & JavaScript With jQuery, CSS & HTML5 (Robin Nixon)
- ❖ CodeIgniter 2 Cookbook
- ❖ HTML & CSS Design and Build Websites Jon DuCkeTT

Language

Arabic : Mother Language

> English: Intermediate